Jordan E Medlock

jordanemedlock@gmail.com

(505) 264-5163

615 La Veta Dr. NE, Albuquerque, NM, 87108

I am interested in pursuing a career in Computer Science. Currently I attend the University of New Mexico working to obtain an undergraduate degree in Computer Science. I have been programming for 6 years, and am a proficient software engineer utilizing a variety of languages in many environments.

Experience

Research Assistant

University of New Mexico Department of Internal Medicine

May 2014 to August 2014

- Created a large Haskell application to find natural product treatments for diseases
- Used a MySQL database to collect protein-target associations
- Found 20,000 treatments for 900 diseases by connecting 3 large databases

Research Assistant

University of New Mexico Pathology Department

January 2014 to September 2014

- Developing Python Scripts to automate genetic information manipulation
- Building and managing the creation of a cluster server
- Creating algorithms to find cancer genes in human genomes

Student Intern

August 2013 to January 2014

- Gained DoD Top Secret, Signals Intelligence Clearance
- Learned software design and engineering through in job projects
- Worked with a team of engineers and clients to create software for use in the agency
- Used PHP, MySQL, and AJAX to create a Web Application to aide compliance missions
- Used Node.js, Python and RabbitMQ to create REST servers to interface with MongoDB for use in compliance missions

Teachers Assistant

University of New Mexico Computer Science Department

January 2013 to Present

- Help intermediate Java programming students with assignments
- Assist instructor with generating class materials
- Grade assignments
- Supplement lectures

Research Assistant

UNM Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology

July 2011 to January 2013

- Created a program to count Alzheimer's Disease plaques in MRIs of mouse brains
- Discussed findings in research meetings
- Reduced the time to count plaques from months to less than 20 seconds

Education

Pursuing a B.S. in Computer Science and Biology

University of New Mexico

NSA

August 2012 to present

Completed 81 credits

1st place Winner

2011-2012 Supercomputing Challenge

Achievements

April 2012

• Competed against over 430 high school students from around the state to create a program to solve a real-world problem

Board Member/Web Master

Umali Autism Foundation Tanzania

Membership

April 2013 to present

• UAFT is a non-profit organization developing educational resources for children with autism in Tanzania, Africa

Strong Knowledge

Technical Skills

Java, Python, Linux/Unix, MATLAB, Haskell, iOS/Android Application programming